Tomie dePaola Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Tomie dePaola Collection.
undated, 1949-1999
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
dePaola, Tomie.
70 linear feet.
Born 15 September 1934 in Meriden, CT. BFA in 1956 at Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, NY. MFA in 1969 from California College of Arts and Crafts, Oakland, California. Three honorary doctorate degrees.
MSS19990033
Biography
Tomie dePaola was born in Meriden, Connecticut in 1934 to Joseph and Florence dePaola. He has two sisters and one brother. His Italian and Irish family background is evident in many of his books. From an early age, Tomie and his parents knew he would be an artist. He received his Bachelor of Fine Arts degree from the Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York where he studied Art. His Master of Fine Arts degree was received from the California College of Arts and Crafts in Oakland, California. He has also been awarded three honorary Doctorate degrees from separate Universities and Colleges.
Tomie's career as a professional artist and designer, former teacher of art, children's author and illustrator is expansive. He has designed greeting cards, posters, magazine and catalogue covers, record album covers, and theater costumes and sets. He has illustrated over two hundred books, and written over seventy. Tomie has won numerous awards, including the prestigious American Library Association's Caldecott Honor Award for Strega Nona (1976), the University of Minnesota's Kerlan Award (1981), the Catholic Library Association's Regina Medal (1983), and the Smithsonian Institution's Smithson Medal (1990).
Tomie's books have been published world-wide in fifteen different languages and he has over five million copies in print. Many of his books are largely autobiographical such as Nana Upstairs, Nana Downstairs, Tom, and The Art Lesson. Tomie currently resides in New Hampshire with his four Welsh Terrier dogs, Madison, Moffat, Morgan and Markus.
Scope and Content
The Tomie dePaola collection contains Tomie's art-work, sketch books and paintings from the beginning of his career, as well as many different editions from each book he wrote or illustrated, including foreign editions. Some of the languages represented are Portuguese, Swedish, Finnish, French Canadian, German, Afrikaans, and even Zulu. Original illustrations from books, as well as paintings and other art work spanning from his childhood years are included. The collection also contains marketing items from his books, such as towels, porcelain jewelry containers, music boxes, paper goods (wrapping paper, cups & plates), quilts from schools, and a large selection of Christmas tree ornaments designed by Tomie.
Arrangement
The series have been broken down into book related marketing materials, over-sized paintings and art work.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of children's literature and associated artwork. Some Cyndy Szekeres illustrations are included in one of Tomie dePaola's sketch books from his years studying at Pratt. Anita Lobel, as well as possibly others, may have also used this same sketch book ( (Series 3, Box 13, Folder #323). For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
Internet source: http://www.opendoor.com/bingley/Bibliographical,
Something About the Author Series, Gale Research; 1992, vol. 15
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Document Types:
Quilts.; Sketchbooks.; Marketing material.; Ornaments.; Books.; Dolls/Stuffed Animals.; Illustrations.; Paintings.
Occupations:
Author.; Artist.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Tomie dePaola in 1999.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Marketing Items for Books, Ornaments, undated, 1978-1999
  - Audio Cassettes (Box 1)
    - Mice Squeak. We Speak, 1999
      - Scholastic Inc., New York
    - Tom, 1994
      - Scholastic Inc., New York
    - Jingle, the Christmas Clown, 1993
      - Scholastic Inc., New York
    - Country Angel Christmas, 1995
      - Children's Book-of-the-Month Club, New York
    - Country Angel Christmas, 1996
      - Scholastic Inc., New York
    - The Tale of Rabbit and Coyote, 1995
      - Scholastic Inc., New York
    - Strega Nona, 1998
      - Record Books Inc., New York
    - I Love You Mouse, 1996
      - Scholastic Inc., New York
    - The Legend of the Poinsettia, 1995
      - Scholastic Inc., NY
    - La Leyenda de la Flor de Nochebuera, 1995
      - Scholastic Inc., NY
    - A Planet With One Mind, 1995
      - One Steps Records, Auburn, CA
        -includes The Legend of the Indian Paintbrush
    - Big Anthony and the Magic Ring, 1996
      - Scholastic Inc., NY
  - Compact Disc (CD)
    - Stranger Than Fiction, 1998
      - “Don't Quit Your Day Job” Records, San Francisco, CA
    - A Planet With One Mind, 1995
      - One Steps Records, Auburn, CA
  - Dolls (Box 2)
    - Strega Nona doll, regular size (from Strega Nona)
    - Strega Nona doll, mini-size (from Strega Nona)
    - (2) She-Who-Is-Alone doll (from The Legend of the Bluebonnet)
    - Petey doll (from Too Many Hopkins)
    - Flossie doll (from Too Many Hopkins)
    - Maggie's Monster (from Maggie and the Monster) (Box 3)
    - Goose (from Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose)
    - Mary, Mary Quite Contrary doll (from Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose)
    - Hickory Dickory Dock doll (from Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose)
    - Humpty Dumpty doll (from Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose)
  - Marketing Items (Box 4)
    - Country Angel Christmas porcelain music box, undated
    - Country Angel cast iron bookends, undated
    - Country Angel musical waterglobe, undated
    - Country Angel cast iron stocking hanger, undated
    - Petey & Flossie picture frame (from Too Many Hopkins), undated
    - Country Angel Christmas stocking, 1996
    - Country Angel bookend set, 1996
    - Merry Christmas plate and set, 1996
    - Strega Nona pillow, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Angel ornaments (by TdP, sewn by Jill Chadwick), 1996; 2
    - Whitebird ornament (by TdP, sewn by Jill Chadwick), 1996
    - Plastic cut-out of men & women holding hands, 1996
    - Prayer pegged wall plaque, 1996
    - Happy Holidays Country Angel pillow, 1996
    - Big Anthony Kaleidoscope, 1996
    - Strega Nona & Big Anthony Bookend pair, 1996
    - Blow up “Kiss” w/ suction cup, undated
  - Quilts from Schools (Box 6)
    - Quilt: “I Love Reading”, undated
    - Wrenshall Elementary School, Wrenshall, Minnesota
    - Quilt, 1st Grade, undated (Box 7)
    - Springfield Elementary School, New Middletown, Ohio
    - Quilt, 1985
    - L. Payne, “CT / OR”
    - Quilt, 2nd Grade, undated (Box 8)
    - Timber Ridge Elementary School, Marietta, GA
    - Quilt, 1st Grade, 1991
    - North Landing Elementary School, Virginia Beach, VA
    - Plaque w/ illustration, 1985
    - Cathedral School, Portland, Oregon
    - Sheet w/ artwork by kids, fourth grade, undated
    - Rippling Woods School, Glen Burnie, MD
    - “Jingle” apron, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Woodglen Elementary School
    - Embroidered Vinyl Flag, undated
    - Features Tomie's Dove
    - Quilt, 2nd Grade, undated
    - O'Loughlin Elementary School, Hays, Kansas
    - Sheet w/ artwork by kids, first grade, undated
    - Gardiner School, Chagrin Falls, Ohio
    - Quilt, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Bartholomew County, Indiana
    - Small Quilt, 1992
    - Bartholomew County, Indiana
    - Michael Bird Boy Marketing Items (Box 11)
      - Large, peach, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Medium, green, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Medium, peach, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Medium, purple, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Large, purple, vinyl, string bag, undated
      - Medium, purple, vinyl, string bag, undated
      - Medium, green, vinyl, string bag, undated
      - Small, peach, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Extra small, peach, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Extra small, purple, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Extra small, green, vinyl, zippered bag, undated
      - Medium, peach, vinyl, zippered bag with handle, undated
      - Medium, green, vinyl, zippered bag with handle, undated
      - Large photo album, undated
      - Medium photo album, undated
      - Medium photo album, plastic cover, undated
    - Michael Bird Boy Ceramic Marketing Items (Box 12)
      - Goblet-shaped, miniature cup (different illustrations), undated; 3
      - Small jug with cork, undated; 1
      - Medium milk bottle with cork, undated; 1
      - Small, square plaques (different illustrations), undated; 3
      - Small, circular plaques (different illustrations), undated; 3
      - Small spoons, undated; 3
      - Miniature spoons, undated; 2
      - Napkin Rings (different illustrations), undated; 2
      - Cup w/ illustration, undated; 1
      - Tea cup with handle w/ illustration, undated; 1
      - Cup w/ handle, undated; 1
      - Miniature tea kettle w/ top, undated; 1
      - Medium tea kettle with top, undated; 1
      - Salt and pepper set, undated; 1
      - Tea cup and plate set, undated; 1
      - Wooden musical jewelry box (pink, blue & wood finish), undated; 3
    - Michael Bird Boy Ceramic (unless specified) Marketing Items (Box 13)
      - Ceramic bank with illustration, undated; 1
      - Heart-shaped jewelry containers, undated; 3
      - Small heart-shaped jewelry containers (diff. illustrations), undated; 2
      - Small circular jewelry containers, undated; 2
      - Small oval jewelry containers (different illustrations), undated; 2
      - Small oval tray, undated; 1
      - Small square trays (different illustrations), undated; 2
      - Small circular trays (different illustrations), undated; 5
      - Small egg-shaped jewelry container, undated; 1
      - Large egg-shaped jewelry container, undated; 1
      - Hooks (different illustrations), undated; 3
      - Large circular tray, undated; 1
      - Small oval picture frame, undated; 1
      - Medium square picture frame, undated; 1
      - Medium planter & saucer, undated; 1
      - Small planter & saucer, undated; 1
      - Miniature planter & saucer, undated; 1
      - Ceramic bell, undated; 1
  - Towels designed by Tomie dePaola (Box 14)
    - Michael Bird Boy bath towels, undated; 6
    - Michael Bird Boy hand towels, undated; 5
    - Michael Bird Boy wash towels, undated; 5
  - “Big Tree” ornaments featured at Marshall Field's State Street Store, Chicago
    - Prince, undated (Box 15)
    - Footman, undated (Box 16)
    - Stepsister; in yellow dress & black hair, undated (Box 17)
    - Cinderella, undated
    - Cinderella's glass slipper, undated (Box 18)
    - Candelabra, undated
    - Pumpkin carriage, undated
    - Stepsister; in pink dress & blonde hair, undated (Box 19)
    - Fairy Godmother, undated
    - Fairy Godmother's wand, undated (Box 20)
    - Candelabra shaped like pear tree, undated (Box 21)
    - Basket of three pear candles
    - I Love You Mouse oversized mock-book for marketing, undated (Box (not in box))
    - Jingle, the Christmas Clown Standee, undated (Box 22)
    - Hark! A Christmas Sampler standee, undated
    - Bonjour, Mr. Satie standee, undated
    - Miracle on 34th Street standee, undated
    - 26 Fairmont Avenue standee and marketing bookmark, undated
    - Nana Upstairs & Nana Downstairs standee & card, undated
    - Four Stories for Four Seasons oversize promotional cover, undated
    - Bill and Pete standee, undated
    - Strega Nona Meets Her Match standee, undated
    - Big Anthony: His Story standee, undated
    - Big Anthony, His Story canvas bag, undated (Box 23)
    - 26 Fairmount Avenue canvas bag, undated
    - SCBWI canvas bag illustrated by Tomie, undated
  - Family Line Paper Products & Country Angel products, 1987 (Box 24)
    - Hey Diddle Diddle gift wrapping paper, 1roll
    - Mother Goose gift wrapping paper, 1roll
    - Hey Diddle Diddle gift wrapping paper (sheets)
    - Mother Goose gift wrapping paper (sheets)
    - Hey Diddle Diddle paper gift bag
    - Mother Goose paper gift bag
    - Hey Diddle Diddle paper table cover
    - Mother Goose paper table cover
    - Hey Diddle Diddle paper napkins
    - Mother Goose paper napkins
    - Hey Diddle Diddle party invitations
    - Mother Goose party invitations
    - Hey Diddle Diddle gift tags (set of 6)
    - Mother Goose gift tags (set of 6)
    - Hey Diddle Diddle paper plates 9″
    - Hey Diddle Diddle paper plates 7″
    - Mother Goose paper plates 9″
    - Mother Goose paper plates 7″
    - Country Angel Christmas holiday tin, 1
    - Country Angel Christmas box of Christmas cards
    - Country Angel Christmas gift bag, 1
    - Paper Goods -not from Family Line
      - Nieman Marcus shopping bag, 1982; 1
      - “Famers” gift bag, 1989; 1
      - Country Angel Christmas afghan, 1996 (Box 25)
      - Country Angel large picture frame, 1996
      - Medium graphic pattern picture frame w/ picture of Tomie, 1996
      - Small picture frame with angels, 1996
      - Sunflower plaque with peg, 1996
      - Strega Nona waterglobe, 1996
      - Strega Nona ball ornament in red box, 1996
      - Country Angel ball ornament in red box, 1996
      - Garland, 1996 (Box 26)
      - Country Angel Christmas Santa doll, 1996
      - Country Angel Christmas accompanying angel dolls, 1996 (Othertype 2)
      - Wagon, 1996
      - Clock, 1996
      - Small shelf, 1996
      - Door arch, “Blessed are the Beasts & Children”, 1996
      - Metal, nativity wreath, 1996
      - Angel tree topper, 1996 (Box 27)
      - Star tree topper, 1996
      - Bird tree topper, 1996
      - Ornaments (manufactured by Midwest), 1996 (Box 28)
      - Ornaments, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Ornaments, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Ornaments (Midwest of Cannon Falls), 1996 (Box 31)
      - Ornaments (Midwest of Cannon Falls), 1996 (Box 32)
      - I Love You Sun, I Love You Moon puzzle, undated (Box 33)
      - Michael Bird Boy puzzle, undated
      - “Happy Holidays” decorative sled, 1996 (Box 34)
      - Jointed Santa display piece, 1996
      - Postcards from Books (4): Tomie dePaola,His Art & His Stories, The Surprise Party, The Night Before Christmas, Andy: That's My Name, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1)
      - Bookmarks for Marketing (5): The Clown of God (2), 1978 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - The Lady of Guadalupe, “There's Magic in Reading” (2), undated
      - Marketing Pamphlets & Cards (8): Jingle the Christmas Clown, For Every Child a Star, Charlie Needs a Cloak, Strega Nona, The Cat on the Doverfell, The Clown of God, “Notable Children's Books”, undated, 1978, 1984 (Box 35:, Folder 3)
      - American Bookseller (Catalog). Cover & p.44, 1982 Spring (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Better Homes & Gardens Country Home. Smith, Linda J. “Artist in Residence”; 7:3 pps.31-41, 1985 June (Box 35:, Folder 5)
      - Bright Ideas. “Tomie dePaola, His Story” no.14, p.3, 1997 Summer (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Holiday House Book Catalog. Cover & pps.30-31,43..., 1995 (Box 35:, Folder 7)
      - Putnam Children's Books (Catalog). p.30-31, 1998 April - August (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Exhibit Flyer: “The Heart of the Whitebird: The Art of Tomie dePaola”, 1999 October - December (Box 35:, Folder 9)
      - Medalions (1): “Welcome Home Tomie” - Meriden Library, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence- Miscellaneous, 1996 (Box 35:, Folder 11)
      - Marshall Field's Christmas Tree “Big O ornaments” -copy of photograph, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Photograph (1) - unidentified, undated (Box 35:, Folder 13)
  - Popcorn tins designed byTomie
    - “We Wish You a Merry Christmas” large popcorn tin, undated
    - “Miracle on 34th Street / Santa” large popcorn tin, undated
    - “Country Angel Christmas” large popcorn tin, undated
    - “Snowman” large popcorn tin, undated
    - “Carolers” large popcorn tin, undated
    - “Christmas Tree” large popcorn tin, undated
    - “The Night Before Christmas” small popcorn tin, undated
    - “Pierrot / Valentine's Day” small popcorn tin, undated
    - “Thanksgiving” small popcorn tin, undated
    - Table & chair designed by Tomie, undated
    - Doll bench, undated
    - Strega Nona piñata
- Series II: Paintings, undated, 1953-1978
  - Autobiographical Mural Study, 1953 (Othertype Painting # 1)
    Casein on masonite
    14″ (h) × 16 1/4;″ (w)
  - Peasant Woman, 1954 (Othertype 2)
    Oil on canvas
    36″ (h) × 11″ (w)
  - Self Portrait, 1954 (Othertype 3)
    19″ × 29″
  - (from a Psalm), 1955 (Othertype 4)
    20″ (h) × 30″ (w)
  - (from a Psalm), 1955 (Othertype 5)
    26″ (h) × 20″ (w)
  - Geraniums, 1955 (Othertype 6)
    18″ (h) × 24″ (w)
  - Landscape- Skowhegan, Maine, 1955 (Othertype 7 (standing))
    26″ (h) × 32″ (w)
  - Stigmata of Francis of Assisi, 1955 (Othertype 8)
    28″ (h) × 20″ (w)
  - Madonna and Child, ca. 1955-1956 (Othertype 9)
    40 1/4″ (h) × 18″ (w)
  - The Good Shepherd, 1956 (Othertype 10)
    36″ (h) × 24″ (w)
  - Woman with Orange, 1956 (Othertype 11)
    Casein on illustration board
    36″ (h) × 8 1/2″ (w)
  - Sanctuary, 1961 (Othertype 12 (standing))
    34 1/2″ (h) × 48″ (w)
  - Virgin of Advent, 1961 (Othertype 13)
  - Boy in Boat, 1962 (Othertype 14)
  - Still Life, 1962 (Othertype 15)
    38″ (h) × 28″ (w)
  - Alice B. Toklas, 1964 (Othertype 16)
    20″ (h) × 16″ (w)
  - Lot's Wife, 1964 (Othertype 17)
    32″ (h) × 24″ (w)
  - Madonna and Child, 1964 (Othertype 18)
    Oil on masonite
    12″ (h) × 12″ (w)
  - Noah's Ark, 1964 (Othertype 19)
    18″ (h) × 14″ (w)
  - Old Testament Women, 1964 (Othertype 20)
    16″ (h) × 20″ (w)
  - Old Testament Women, 1964 (Othertype 21)
    24″ (h) × 30″ (w)
  - Old Testament Women II, 1964 (Othertype 22)
    20″ (h) × 23″ (w)
  - Three Marys, 1964 (Othertype 23)
    16″ (h) × 12″ (w)
  - FEP, 1966 (Othertype 24 (standing))
    36″ (h) × 36″ (w)
  - Tom and Nana, 1966 (Othertype 25)
    16 1/4″ (h) × 16 1/4″ (w)
  - Cousin Kitty
    ** These two paintings are meant to be hung one above the other.
  - Heart Machine, 1967 (Othertype 26)
    Acrylic on canvas
  - History of a Kiss (Othertype 27)
    - 4 Lips
    - Big Lips
      ** These two painting are meant to be hung one above the other, Big Lips on the bottom.
  - Miner's Shack, 1967 (Othertype 28)
  - Solomon's Temple, 1967 (Othertype 29)
    30″ (h) × 25″ (w)
  - Nine of the Sisters Levitate, 1978 (Othertype 30)
    Pencil and watercolor on paper
    18″ (h) × 18″ (w)
  - (Untitled) Mexican Man and his family, undated; 1957 (Othertype 31)
- Series III: Art Work, undated, 1949-1999
  - “Virgin”- pen & ink on paper (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - “Christ figure” sketch- ballpoint pen on paper, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - “Family Album Portrait”- collograph, rubber stamp & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - “Mae West as Amelia Earhart” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - “Siren” -tempera on illustration board, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - “Hippie Girl” -tempera on illustration board, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - “Malaya” -charcoal on paper, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Satie's Garden -pencil & watercolor on board, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - “Nature Boy Dancing During the Comet Display” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - “The Place of the Inner Altar” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - “Indian Brave...” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - “Mythological creature number one” -pencil & watercolor on board, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - “Comet over nude lady” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - “Emily...” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1979 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - “Centaur” -ink & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - “Annunciation” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Comet Series:, 1971; (5 illustrations) (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - - Comet over Old Faithful geyser
    - - The wedding of the comets
    - - Moon over directional sign
    - - The death of the comet
    - - Comet over Maui
  - “Sky” -collograph, rubber stamp on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - 2 illustrations, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - - “Moon over three Calabrian Cypress” - pencil & watercolor on paper
    - - “Moon and doorway” -ballpoint pen & watercolor on paper
  - “Sun” -scratchboard illustration, ca. 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - “Three Eggs in a Box” -pencil on board, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - “Very Fine is my Valentine...” -ink on paper, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - “Flowers are a wonderful thing...” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - “I Love Gertrude Stein” -marker on paper, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - “Tower of Babel” -tempera on board, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - “Lady in a Canoe” -ink on board, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - “Love, Peace & Joy” -black line plate & overlay, c.1960 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - “Woman with bunny” -pen & ink on paper, c.1960 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - “Upside down rainbow” -pen & watercolor on paper, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - “Cloud” -pen & watercolor on paper, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - “Woman” -pen & watercolor on paper, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - 2 illustrations -marker on inks on paper, ca. 1960s (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - -“Moon”, “Night”
  - “Woman with obelisk” -pen & ink and watercolor paper, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - “Tomie dePaola Esq.” -pen & ink & colored inks on paper, ca. 1962-63 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - “Woman” -ink and Cray-pas on board, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - “The Betrothal” -pen & ink on paper, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - “St. Veronica” -pen & ink on paper”, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - 3 illustrations- pencil & watercolor on paper, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - - Cloud eats room
    - - Tree and moon
    - - Tree w/ Lady, mountain & moon
  - 2 illustrations, ca. 1960s (Box 1:, Folder 39)
    - - “Circle” -pencil on paper
    - - “Sketch” -pen & ink on paper
  - “Belling the Cat” -watercolor on paper, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
  - “Bird” -oil on paper, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
  - “Cross” -pen & ink on paper, ca. mid 1960s (Box 1:, Folder 42)
  - “Woman in red, white & blue dress” -tempera on board, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 43)
  - “Burning bush” -tempera on board, 1964 (Box 1:, Folder 44)
  - “Boy and Moon” -pen & ink & watercolor on board, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 45)
  - “Fishing Nets” -pen & ink on paper, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 46)
  - “Snow White and Rose Red” -pen & ink and colored inks on paper, undated (Box 1:, Folder 47)
  - “The Country Maid and her Milkpail” -colored inks on paper, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 48)
  - “Moon over my Italian Grandmother” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 49)
  - “There was the Tunnel” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 50)
  - “The Artist as a Hermit” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 51)
  - “Desert Scene” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 52)
  - Sketch of cat -ink on paper, undated (Box 1:, Folder 53)
  - “It's Time for the Winter Festival to Begin” -pencil, white pencil crayon & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
  - “Tweet” -pencil & watercolor & rubber stamp on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 55)
  - “The Good Red Road...” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 56)
  - “White peacock on a plinth...” -pencil, watercolor & tempera on paper, undated (Box 1:, Folder 57)
  - 4 Illustrations -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 58)
    - - “The only amphora left is behind the mountain”
    - - “Moon, amphora and plinth”
    - - “Moon and cloud over Vermont”
    - - “Priestess, amphora and moon”
  - “Valentine for Gertrude Stein & Gertrude Patch” -collograph, rubber stamp & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 59)